Justin Cheng

New York, NY 10029 | https://justincheng2.netlify.app/ | www.linkedin.com/in/chengjustin0222/

A third-year student pursuing a BS in Information Management & Technology with a focus in Front end development Classroom experience in high-demand programming languages along with experience in supporting educational IT infrastructure. Exploring for summer 2023 internships.

EDUCATION

Syracuse University, iSchool for Information Studies – Syracuse, NY

September 2020 - December 2023

Major: Information Management & Technology

GPA: 3.68

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- HTML5/CSS3
- React.JS
- JavaScript
- Cert. Microsoft Office Excel Associate
- Node.JS

NEXT.JS

- - Agile Methodology

Tailwind/SCSS

- Figma
- Python
- Mandarin (Speaking)

FRONT END WEB APPLICATIONS

- GitHub: https://github.com/jcheng01
- Created single web page using React and Tailwind to fetch JSON resources from two APIs. The goal is to demonstrate how an AI can understand a randomly generated image by parsing through outputted information
- Used Pokémon API to create an application using React.js and Tailwind imitating a database. The single page returns respective Pokémon data from rest API server using entered name
- Personal Website created with raw HTML/SCSS/JavaScript. Implemented my own webpack to compile JS. Fun selfproject to work on responsive components

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- IST 263 Principles for construction and publication of multimedia documents for the Web. Incorporate a user-based approach to planning, design, implementation, and management with an entrepreneurial perspective and with a focus on client/enterprise
- IST 256 Students learn practical applications of computer programming with Python such as how to automate tasks, manipulate data and solve problems applicable to almost any academic discipline.
- IST 363 Utilized PHP and custom theming with WordPress. At the end coordinate the applications React with WordPress in Next.js to customize professional front-end imitation restaurant website
- **IST 466 (current)** Capstone course for Information Management and Technology majors. It is an integration of management strategies, information uses, and information technologies as related to professional conduct, ethics, and career strategies. In-depth review and use of case studies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Syracuse University - iSchool

Syracuse, NY

Student Technology Consultant

September 2022 – Present

- Collaborate with other IT department staff to resolve inquiries and ensure quality support at a rate of 100%
- Providing technical support over the phone and in person, including configuration of student MS outlook, SU Blackboard, and AirOrangeX
- Trained in iSchool technology help desk resources, policies, and services to provide technical support over the phone and in person, and maintaining the smooth operation of the iSchool facilities

Syracuse University – Barnes Center

Syracuse, NY

Front Desk Receptionist

September 2020 – December 2021

- Provided excellent patron service, effectively maintaining a 99% satisfaction rate
- Answered Queries on wide-ranging service concerns utilizing facility virtual catalog